<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Forethinker - life</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.4thinker.com/</id><updated>2016-06-06T14:45:14-07:00</updated><entry><title>My Choice of Hardware in 2016</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/gadgets-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-06T14:45:14-07:00</published><updated>2016-06-06T14:45:14-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2016-06-06:/gadgets-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Phone | Nexus 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still running strong after three years. I am waiting for Nexus 2016 with Android N. My folks are still using Nexus 5 with no problem. They will probably get a refresh once Nexus 2016 price drops in about a year after the release. Nexus 6P dropped about 33% in price after 9 months of release. I can't wait for my phone to replace my credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Camera | Pentax K-50&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weatherproof and best bang for the buck in the entry-level camera. I use 50mm prime with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Laptop | Dell M3800&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best laptop I used and nothing else …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Phone | Nexus 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still running strong after three years. I am waiting for Nexus 2016 with Android N. My folks are still using Nexus 5 with no problem. They will probably get a refresh once Nexus 2016 price drops in about a year after the release. Nexus 6P dropped about 33% in price after 9 months of release. I can't wait for my phone to replace my credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Camera | Pentax K-50&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weatherproof and best bang for the buck in the entry-level camera. I use 50mm prime with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Laptop | Dell M3800&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best laptop I used and nothing else compares to it. The CPU power has not improved much since 2013. The introduction of Sandy Bridge was huge, (Ivy Bridge, tick) the next tock Haswell was a pretty good improvement in both performance and energy consumption. (Broadwell, tick) But Skylake only offers slight improvement over its predecessors, where the upgrade is not as significant to justify the upgrade. It comes with HDMI 2.0 for 4k 60hz, DDR4, USB-C. But I see them as nice to haves instead of necessities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Server | Synology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you use it, you can't never go back. It is a pleasure to use, low maintenance, and reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Monitor | LG IPS236-PN 23"&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tired Dell 34 inch Ultrawide monitor (U3415W). If you are adept with keyboard shortcuts and have the windows management system ready, 34 inch monitor is more of a distraction than a productivity enhancer. My current monitor + laptop screen provide plenty of screen estate for me. I think 1080p is the standard for most places, so connecting and disconnecting external monitors do not disarrange windows placement. Also having HDMI and audio output is great so that I could have a dedicated speakers / earphones for my home setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Power Bank | DBPower DJS20&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12000mah battery bank to power my phones, gadgets, laptop, and even car battery in case of an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Minimalist Camera Setup</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/dslr-camera-lens.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-07T17:44:16-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-07T17:44:16-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2016-04-07:/dslr-camera-lens.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The argument for 35mm vs 50mm is endless and I finally came to peace with my choice.
I own Pentax K-50, an excellent entry camera for a hobbyist. After playing around with the zoom lens kit (18-55), I bought my first prime lens with 55mm focal length.
I did feel some uneasiness when I tried to take group photo, or any indoor photo that needed a bit more landscape. &lt;a href="http://www.pentaxforums.com/forums/58-troubleshooting-beginner-help/259160-my-first-prime-lens-pentax-da-50mm-f1-8-vs-da-35mm-f2-4-al.html"&gt;From the Pentax Forum, 2/3 of the users recommended 35mm.&lt;/a&gt;. I was a click away from buying 35mm lens, but then after some research. I decided to invest more money …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The argument for 35mm vs 50mm is endless and I finally came to peace with my choice.
I own Pentax K-50, an excellent entry camera for a hobbyist. After playing around with the zoom lens kit (18-55), I bought my first prime lens with 55mm focal length.
I did feel some uneasiness when I tried to take group photo, or any indoor photo that needed a bit more landscape. &lt;a href="http://www.pentaxforums.com/forums/58-troubleshooting-beginner-help/259160-my-first-prime-lens-pentax-da-50mm-f1-8-vs-da-35mm-f2-4-al.html"&gt;From the Pentax Forum, 2/3 of the users recommended 35mm.&lt;/a&gt;. I was a click away from buying 35mm lens, but then after some research. I decided to invest more money on my next cell phone.  Cellphone cameras have 26-29mm equivalent focal length. So, let's consider the use cases for 35mm lens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;35mm: photos which include the environment with the subject; groups of people; use in a tight space; or landscape photography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use cases matches cellphone pretty well. You would usually share these with friends and cell phone has sharing ability to make these happen quickly. I do think I can skip DSLR for these photos. But I could also now see why the people on the forum suggested 35mm. It is the focal length people are most comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let's look at the use cases for 50mm:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50mm: one person photos; keeping a little distance; and more bokeh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say you need DSLR for these. These are special pictures that need a bit more of attention and post-processing. If you want to read more about the difference, here is &lt;a href="http://www.paulcoatesphoto.com/2013/06/which-lens-35mm-or-50mm.html"&gt;a good comparison between 35mm and 50mm in depth&lt;/a&gt;. If I am out in a good weather and there is a possibility of water, I could opt for zoom lens since I don't have to worry too much about the aperture and forego cell phone camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a decent cellphone and DSLR + 50mm, most use cases will be covered. Yes, some scenario will not be covered, a group photo in a low-light setting, for instance, but I think this is a nice compromise. In conclusion, I was forgetting to utilize cellphone camera thinking that it is just inferior to DSLR. My current camera is a bit on the low-tier side, but it is definitely underutilized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR: cell phone for wide, DSLR for macro, zoom lens for good weather/waterproof&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="camera"></category><category term="dslr"></category><category term="lens"></category></entry><entry><title>What I want in a phone</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/cellphone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-02T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-01-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2016-01-02:/cellphone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Wanted Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stock Android: Google's Android features get updated very frequently. A lot has change since I first got Nexus 5 and it is still updating earlier than other brands'. Software is the heart of a machine and I would rather choose stock Android even if I have to sacrifice other features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fast charging: I am waiting for Snapdragon 820 really badly right now. Reportedly, Huawei is making a successor to Nexus 6P in 2016 with snapdragon 820. I think this is going my next phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replaceable battery: with the fast charging and a bigger battery, the need for a …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Wanted Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stock Android: Google's Android features get updated very frequently. A lot has change since I first got Nexus 5 and it is still updating earlier than other brands'. Software is the heart of a machine and I would rather choose stock Android even if I have to sacrifice other features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fast charging: I am waiting for Snapdragon 820 really badly right now. Reportedly, Huawei is making a successor to Nexus 6P in 2016 with snapdragon 820. I think this is going my next phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replaceable battery: with the fast charging and a bigger battery, the need for a replaceable battery will be gone, but upgradability still matters. The battery health will give in after a year or two. Especially with the phone becoming a commodity and much more durable, I might end up using my next phone for 4 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;physical buttons: I was a fan of utilizing the entire screen of a phone, but when I used Samsung Note 5, I found that sometimes these buttons are not responsive. I found a few others complaining about it on the web. If the manufacturer can get this right and it can be used comfortably with one hand, then it would be great. But I could live without it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meh Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big screen: it really depends on the ergonomics. But I see both pros and cons in screen sizes. I am happy with either, but I'd opt for something in between like 5.3"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rear buttons: if it works well, I am okay with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB-C: this does not make that much difference in my work flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aluminum bodies: it is nice to have, but I'd rather have a rugged design like LG V10 so that I don't have to put an extra case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samsung Pay: it is a nice to have, but I'd rather hand over my card than my phone when I go through a drive-through&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speakers: I am usually at a public place, so I don't need any good speakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wireless charging: although I really cannot use my phone properly while it is being charge. This can be great if I use it in my car, but the charging efficiency is still a problem. The power draw of GPS will drain the battery despite the wireless charging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stylus:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Noway Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curved display: this makes sense for a big monitor or a TV, not so much for a phone. A foldable phone makes sense.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curved edge: it is a marketing gimmick that kills usability. How are you suppose to use a phone properly when you need a good grip?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secondary screen: this means non-stock android. I want to avoid proprietary features as much as possible. Also there is a good chance that it won't be good because not many softwares utilize it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SD card: I thought I needed this. But I don't after removing data cap on my phone. I stream everything now and it is more convenient that way. If I were to use my phone for a different purpose or use it for ROM testing, I might need it, but I am going to use my phone as a phone, not as a computer or a server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Ubiquitous features in 2016&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fingerprint sensors: the compatibility with lastpass is great. Also no need for a gesture password!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;camera quality: I realized that this is very important to capture precious moments in life. Most flagships' camera quality are good, so I am less worried about this now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlimited Data (~6GB): it is amazing when you can thether and start working on your laptop. Also a lot of hassles of moving pictures, video, and music can be gone if you start embracing streaming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coverage: Verizon dominates in this. If you have an international phone. Having an ability to switch to a SIM card that utilizes Verizon network would be great when you go travelling into the wild.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bluetooth headset: I haven't found one with a good mouthpiece, and charging is another task to do everyday. I ditch blutooth headset for a wired one. It can be useful when I am running, but that is about it. I am okay with wired one in any situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="phone"></category><category term="android"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="features"></category><category term="hardware"></category></entry><entry><title>I am addicted to perrier and I cannot lie</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/perrier.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2015-12-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-12-17:/perrier.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So carbonated water is much healthier than other types of drink for your bones and teeth according to [BBC] (http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20150911-is-sparkling-water-really-bad-for-you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That weak acid, however, seems to be beneficial to my digestive system, especially when I eat a lot after a workout or something. And also that refreshing feeling from the carbonation makes my brain happy. Perrier's carbonating technique seems to be a lot superior to its competitors. The kick is much stronger and it lasts longer after the bottle has been opened.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So carbonated water is much healthier than other types of drink for your bones and teeth according to [BBC] (http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20150911-is-sparkling-water-really-bad-for-you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That weak acid, however, seems to be beneficial to my digestive system, especially when I eat a lot after a workout or something. And also that refreshing feeling from the carbonation makes my brain happy. Perrier's carbonating technique seems to be a lot superior to its competitors. The kick is much stronger and it lasts longer after the bottle has been opened.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diet"></category><category term="perrier"></category><category term="carbonated"></category></entry><entry><title>Why do you bother charging your wireless devices?</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/charging-devices.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-16T09:43:50-08:00</published><updated>2015-12-16T09:43:50-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-12-16:/charging-devices.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love technology, but there is one trait of a device that is a turn off for me. And that is charging. Okay, I do make a compromise and I understand that I cannot live with just wired devices. Here are a few indispensable devices that need charging in my inventory: laptop and cellphone. My vacuum cleaner does not make it to this list because it has a dock. My kindle... it lasts a month and it gets charged as I think about which book or documents to transfer my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I skip wireless mouse, headset, selfie-stick, battery pack …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love technology, but there is one trait of a device that is a turn off for me. And that is charging. Okay, I do make a compromise and I understand that I cannot live with just wired devices. Here are a few indispensable devices that need charging in my inventory: laptop and cellphone. My vacuum cleaner does not make it to this list because it has a dock. My kindle... it lasts a month and it gets charged as I think about which book or documents to transfer my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I skip wireless mouse, headset, selfie-stick, battery pack, or watch. It is an extra burden on my part to keep their juices up and high. The only time when I find bluetooth is really handy in my routine is when I get into my car. The phone syncs up with the microphone and the speakers. But I do not need to charge those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireless devices are much easier to lose too.  Call me old school, but I am perfectly fine with wires.  &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Construction Communication Tactics in Relationship</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/relationship.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2015-11-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-11-19:/relationship.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Notes from the book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Our-Sexuality-Robert-L-Crooks/dp/0495811793/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1447982849&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=our+sexuality"&gt;"Our Sexuality" by Robert L. Crooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gottman's Constructive Communication Tactics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leveling: stating our thought and feelings clearly, simply, and honestly: preferably using "I" language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing: avoid saying things that are hurtful and expressing only the information that are relevant to the issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validating: facilitating constructive dialogue by acknowledging the reasonableness of our partner's concern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volatile Dialogue: some degree of conflict is essential to the long-term happiness of a relationship. For a long-term relationship (&amp;gt; 3 years), the couple who argued occasionally reported significantly more relationship satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gottman's Destructive Communication Tactics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Criticism: "you" statements that attack's one's character …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Notes from the book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Our-Sexuality-Robert-L-Crooks/dp/0495811793/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1447982849&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=our+sexuality"&gt;"Our Sexuality" by Robert L. Crooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gottman's Constructive Communication Tactics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leveling: stating our thought and feelings clearly, simply, and honestly: preferably using "I" language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing: avoid saying things that are hurtful and expressing only the information that are relevant to the issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validating: facilitating constructive dialogue by acknowledging the reasonableness of our partner's concern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volatile Dialogue: some degree of conflict is essential to the long-term happiness of a relationship. For a long-term relationship (&amp;gt; 3 years), the couple who argued occasionally reported significantly more relationship satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gottman's Destructive Communication Tactics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Criticism: "you" statements that attack's one's character instead of addressing the issue at hand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contempt: conveying emotions and thought via insults, sarcasm, and name calling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defensiveness: excuses, denying responsibility, replying back with a criticism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stonewalling: silence, avoidance, ignoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belligerence: provoking style of interaction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love triangle theory: passion, intimacy, and commitment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Six different love styles: romantic, game playing, possessive, compassionate, altruistic, and pragmatic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The transition from passion to deep attraction result from gradual increase of endorphins in the brain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Factors for interpersonal attractions are: similarity, reciprocity, and physical attractiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parents play a great role in shaping their children's social competence and relationship skills. Securely attached adults can build stable and satisfying relationships and do not fear of being abandoned because they have a good self-image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Should I get into photography</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/photography.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-27T10:11:16-07:00</published><updated>2015-04-27T10:11:16-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-04-27:/photography.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been seriously contemplating buying a DSLR, especially a Pentax k50, because it is weatherproof and accordingly snapsort, it is fairs pretty well compared to other brand names like Canon and Nikkon. I was about to buy a bundle from Adorama.com because they were on sale and then I stopped. I had 2 Point-and-Shoot cameras lingering in the closet. I hardly used them. I hardly got into photography when I bought decent PoS years back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reasoned with myself. Will I get into photography if I buy a good camera? There was obviously no, but I still was …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been seriously contemplating buying a DSLR, especially a Pentax k50, because it is weatherproof and accordingly snapsort, it is fairs pretty well compared to other brand names like Canon and Nikkon. I was about to buy a bundle from Adorama.com because they were on sale and then I stopped. I had 2 Point-and-Shoot cameras lingering in the closet. I hardly used them. I hardly got into photography when I bought decent PoS years back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reasoned with myself. Will I get into photography if I buy a good camera? There was obviously no, but I still was about to blow a couple hundred dollars for a few pictures that I will actually keep around. Maybe those pictures won't be that good, but the sunken cost of my time will make them save-worthy in my hard drives somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't use social network, and I don't use photo frames, so the photography was not for myself, but for someone who would appreciate it, like friends or families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I still needed some article confirming that I don't need one. And no photography website will ever discourage their fan base from getting into pro-photograph, so it took me a while to nail down the website -- on &lt;a href="http://www.popsci.com/gadgets/article/2012-08/dont-buy-dslr"&gt;popular science&lt;/a&gt;. This got blasted by people at &lt;a href="http://www.dpreview.com/forums/thread/3271474#forum-post-42559932"&gt;dpreview&lt;/a&gt;, but this was good enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my decision? Sticking with my android phone. Why, because the simplicity is the best thing in life. If I plan on going to a trip for a year or so, I will buy a mirrorless camera, but until then I am putting photography aside and focusing on other things. Sorry my thought flow was not very coherent, but after spending hours of debating, I predict that I will get into many conflict and I won't know the answers to these questions until I spend a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've decided that photography is in the league of Chinese Weigi(Go) for me - very time consuming to the point where the enjoyment of doing it will be shadowed by the regrets of missing other opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Operating Systems</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/operating-systems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-16T13:28:15-07:00</published><updated>2015-03-16T13:28:15-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-03-16:/operating-systems.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html"></content></entry><entry><title>Beats Solo 2.0 vs Other earphones</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/beats-solo-2.0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-07T14:44:41-08:00</published><updated>2015-01-07T14:44:41-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-01-07:/beats-solo-2.0.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am listening to my favorite artist with &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00IYA2YRK/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00IYA2YRK&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=forethinker-20&amp;amp;linkId=RDNR3NB74I6GNALI"&gt;Beats Solo 2.0 Wired On-Ear Headphones&lt;/a&gt; right now. It sounds great. Maybe it is because of the bigger cone, I can tell the dynamic range of the song and the bass is very lively. I have never been a fan of on-ear earphone because of their size. I am a minimalist and I like to keep things simple. Also my ears are sensitive to temperature and on-ear earphone does not help in that regard. The voice-cancelling earphones are good enough for me in most cases, and I tend to opt for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am listening to my favorite artist with &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00IYA2YRK/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00IYA2YRK&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=forethinker-20&amp;amp;linkId=RDNR3NB74I6GNALI"&gt;Beats Solo 2.0 Wired On-Ear Headphones&lt;/a&gt; right now. It sounds great. Maybe it is because of the bigger cone, I can tell the dynamic range of the song and the bass is very lively. I have never been a fan of on-ear earphone because of their size. I am a minimalist and I like to keep things simple. Also my ears are sensitive to temperature and on-ear earphone does not help in that regard. The voice-cancelling earphones are good enough for me in most cases, and I tend to opt for LG Bluetooth earphones so that I don't have to worry about the wires. So I am debating whether I should sell or give away this headphone that I just received as a gift.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Earphones"></category></entry><entry><title>Heartache of being a Good Sport</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/heartache.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-18T21:04:33-08:00</published><updated>2014-12-18T21:04:33-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-12-18:/heartache.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I go through my own share of heartaches. For me, I see an heartache as feeling the emptiness in my heart. It is like hunger, you've got to stuff your heart with something in order to avoid the pain. Unfortunately, often life is not in your control and things are taken away from you, or the things that you were expecting never comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People try very hard to fill up this space, because if they don't they would get depressed or even suicidal. Some people do it with alcohol, sex, drugs, food, work, fame, TV, and while others do it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I go through my own share of heartaches. For me, I see an heartache as feeling the emptiness in my heart. It is like hunger, you've got to stuff your heart with something in order to avoid the pain. Unfortunately, often life is not in your control and things are taken away from you, or the things that you were expecting never comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People try very hard to fill up this space, because if they don't they would get depressed or even suicidal. Some people do it with alcohol, sex, drugs, food, work, fame, TV, and while others do it with family, religion, philanthropy, and voluntary works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've done an experiment with myself. I tried to remove anything that is not good or productive: porn, game, TV, Facebook, alcohol, drugs, smoking. I would say I was successful but I got depressed like crazy. Filling it up with things that are good is not easy. It is like eating vegetables all the time. I think this is why some people go into mountains or remote place in order to undergo spiritual training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest part here is not able to connect with other people as much anymore. It is like you are the only vegetarian among the crowd. My beliefs and lifestyle are so different that I get lonely beyond words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just to hope to find one person who shares a lot of my beliefs and lifestyle and spend the rest of my life together happily.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>lighter fonts on darker screen</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/black-on-white.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-06T15:46:39-08:00</published><updated>2014-12-06T15:46:39-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-12-06:/black-on-white.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been debating whether I should have a black background on white. I used to have a superstition that a dark background is always better than a white background. I was so obsessive with this configuration that I changed everything, including a web browser to have a black background. I achieved this by various methods, but I was crazy enough to define color scheme for every tag combination on Firefox Stylish. When I couldn't use Firefox Stylish, I tired CSS inverse method on Google Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it got annoying, because they just wouldn't work perfectly. For example, The Google …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been debating whether I should have a black background on white. I used to have a superstition that a dark background is always better than a white background. I was so obsessive with this configuration that I changed everything, including a web browser to have a black background. I achieved this by various methods, but I was crazy enough to define color scheme for every tag combination on Firefox Stylish. When I couldn't use Firefox Stylish, I tired CSS inverse method on Google Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it got annoying, because they just wouldn't work perfectly. For example, The Google Chrome would flash when I scroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think dark background is definitely better if you switch places often and find yourself in different light settings. But if you can have a consistent lightning or get your screen to adjust to the ambient light settings, light font on dark screen is better &lt;a href="http://ux.stackexchange.com/questions/53264/dark-or-white-color-theme-is-better-for-the-eyes"&gt;not just from the UX point of view, but for your comprehension.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finding that out, I switched my solarized dark scheme to light scheme. I am so happy. Lighter color makes everything more luxurious.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ux"></category></entry><entry><title>Daily Devotional Every Night</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/daily-devotional.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-24T15:33:41-08:00</published><updated>2014-11-24T15:33:41-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-11-24:/daily-devotional.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I try to read &lt;a href="http://www.baptistbiblehour.org/resources/devotionals/"&gt;bbh Daily Devotion&lt;/a&gt; every night &lt;a href="http://www.baptistbiblehour.org/resources/blog/daily-devotion-app-iphone-and-android/"&gt;with this app on my phone&lt;/a&gt;. I used to do Our Daily Bread, but I wanted some more challenging words, so I went to download all devotional apps available on Android and tried them all and picked bbh as the winner. Anyway, doing devotional is a habit I formed in college, because when I spend entire day working with numbers and figures, my mind is still in the state of "momentum". As in, sometimes I would wake up in the middle of the night with an headache because I would be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I try to read &lt;a href="http://www.baptistbiblehour.org/resources/devotionals/"&gt;bbh Daily Devotion&lt;/a&gt; every night &lt;a href="http://www.baptistbiblehour.org/resources/blog/daily-devotion-app-iphone-and-android/"&gt;with this app on my phone&lt;/a&gt;. I used to do Our Daily Bread, but I wanted some more challenging words, so I went to download all devotional apps available on Android and tried them all and picked bbh as the winner. Anyway, doing devotional is a habit I formed in college, because when I spend entire day working with numbers and figures, my mind is still in the state of "momentum". As in, sometimes I would wake up in the middle of the night with an headache because I would be trying to solve some impossible algorithm problems in my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been doing this for a couple years now, with some big gaps in between, because I just sometimes get too tired or have a lot of other things going on. But despite my lack of dedication, it had a very positive affect in my life. I am happier, more relaxed, and more future-oriented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be awkward in the beginning because it interferes with whatever the routine you had before, but I try not to think too much about it. Or if your let it slip for a while, don't let guilt take over. Guilt, for me, prevents me from directing myself to the right path.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="devotional"></category><category term="christian"></category><category term="sleep"></category><category term="habit"></category></entry><entry><title>Food for thought if you are learning a new language</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/learning-a-new-language.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-16T04:46:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-07-16T04:46:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-07-16:/learning-a-new-language.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know, I see all these videos for learning English, breaking down the grammar structure and vocabulary for every sentence. Then I wonder, how would a baby take in those lessons? I mean 1 year old baby is no smarter than most of you out there. Okay, my smarter I mean, his/her knowledge base is much less than most of you. Maybe someone could argue that knowing less is an advantage, but in my opinion, such academic way of learning a new language is horribly inefficient. Even if you cannot afford to live in the native country for a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know, I see all these videos for learning English, breaking down the grammar structure and vocabulary for every sentence. Then I wonder, how would a baby take in those lessons? I mean 1 year old baby is no smarter than most of you out there. Okay, my smarter I mean, his/her knowledge base is much less than most of you. Maybe someone could argue that knowing less is an advantage, but in my opinion, such academic way of learning a new language is horribly inefficient. Even if you cannot afford to live in the native country for a language, starting out with a children book and a children's TV show to simulate language immersion is a far better option. With a possible exception to the vocabulary (I recommend pictionary = picture + dictionary), learning one language in another language creates too much barriers and fluffs to the essence of the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. I must admit, I am guilty for not proof-reading the posts on this website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="language"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>What should I strive to do as a young software engineer?</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/young-programmer-career.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-13T21:32:50-07:00</published><updated>2014-07-13T21:32:50-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-07-13:/young-programmer-career.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In college, I took classes that interested me and I think it was the best choice I made for my education. People do not look at my grades anymore and a lot of knowledge I gained in college turned out to be exercise for my brain. So what I see is that the depth of your knowledge pays, but the breadth of your knowledge pays even more if you know how to knit them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In college, I lived as busy as I could be and I had not much room to juggle around once I set the schedule for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In college, I took classes that interested me and I think it was the best choice I made for my education. People do not look at my grades anymore and a lot of knowledge I gained in college turned out to be exercise for my brain. So what I see is that the depth of your knowledge pays, but the breadth of your knowledge pays even more if you know how to knit them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In college, I lived as busy as I could be and I had not much room to juggle around once I set the schedule for the quarter. Since the graduation, however, things have changed. I am truly the boss of my life. Right after college, I spent all my time exploring the tools for my trade. I recently spent a good amount of time to form good habits for my health and finance. Now I am looking for something else. You can only stimulate brain so much by doing your job at work. You need to feed yourself with work that will give you the guidance on who you want to be and feel accomplished in things you care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see the following career paths as a software engineer and these are my advices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Engineer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineers tend to get either enamored by million different ideas or get pulled by other people who demand their skills, services, and advices. But I think the best time spent for any software engineer is learning algorithms. You will probably safe-proof any job hunting you might need in the future. It can be fun and stimulating to tackle these problems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Manager:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good managerial skills are not restricted to people who pay 50k a year. You can start reading about it and start practicing right away. If you really think an MBA degree will promote your career, have your company pay for it. If you already have a good people skills, you probably can pull this off. By starting early on your own, you catch two birds with one stone AND get ahead of other people. Here are my recommendation for books:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting to Yes: Negotiating Agreement Without Giving In&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crucial Conversations: Tools for Talking When Stakes Are High &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Five Dysfunctions of a Team: A Leadership Fable &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting Things Done: The Art of Stress-Free Productivity &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People: Powerful Lessons in Personal Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Win Friends &amp;amp; Influence People&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good to Great: Why Some Companies Make the Leap...And Others Don't&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, start now, because I have read these books and I still find myself horrible at the skills these books teach. It probably will take me a lifetime, but I strongly believe that these are skills that have compounding returns, because good social skills attract good people and good people could save you from troubles that you cannot foresee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Startup:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think you are a bit of both mindset (manager, engineer) with a penchant for risks, then start learning javascript. There is a good chance whatever you learn will be useless in the long run, but you will live in excitement that you might be onto something big. Even when you don't have an idea yourself, your (potential) co-founder will be thrilled that you are a javascript expert. If you need some motivation along the way, go read on &lt;a href="techcrunch.com"&gt;techcrunch.com&lt;/a&gt; on what others are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or why not try to be all three at the same time? The depth of your knowledge pays, but the breadth of your knowledge pays even more if you know how to knit them together.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="career"></category><category term="engineer"></category></entry><entry><title>Advices that worked for me in my 20s</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/advices-for-20s.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-13T09:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-07-13T09:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-07-13:/advices-for-20s.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for a job that offers free (healthy) food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a startup company to get the visibility in the company and feel satisfied with your work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even when the rent price is expensive, pay the price to not own/need a car. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of trying to form good habits, block all distractions first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to your imaginary self from 10 years future - then choose your habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't travel too much. Save that for your retirement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for an advice from everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't be afraid to skip things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your expectations low.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read news headlines everyday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep things simple. This allows …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for a job that offers free (healthy) food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a startup company to get the visibility in the company and feel satisfied with your work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even when the rent price is expensive, pay the price to not own/need a car. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of trying to form good habits, block all distractions first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to your imaginary self from 10 years future - then choose your habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't travel too much. Save that for your retirement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for an advice from everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't be afraid to skip things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your expectations low.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read news headlines everyday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep things simple. This allows you to take on more tasks or any new task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nobody really cares about what you have, but they care about what you can offer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absorb knowledge until you feel like your eyes are the bottlenecks for your learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then chill by listening to audiobooks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise just 30 minutes everyday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know thyself and learn to control your emotions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more time with your family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="career"></category><category term="habits"></category></entry><entry><title>Porn is like cigarettes/cocaine to your psychological health.</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/better-without-porn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-27T01:01:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-06-27T01:01:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-06-27:/better-without-porn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I never did drugs in my life, but I have seen their effects, so I am making the comparison. I am not the expert on the topic, but here is the best video I could find on the web: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wSF82AwSDiU"&gt;The Great Porn Experiment: Gary Wilson at TEDxGlasgow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in my life, I thought I could never get away from it. I mean the pleasure (the release of dopamine) is just feels so irresistible because our brain is wired that way. But just as you are able to form a habit (addiction) to it, the steps also can be reversed. You …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I never did drugs in my life, but I have seen their effects, so I am making the comparison. I am not the expert on the topic, but here is the best video I could find on the web: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wSF82AwSDiU"&gt;The Great Porn Experiment: Gary Wilson at TEDxGlasgow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in my life, I thought I could never get away from it. I mean the pleasure (the release of dopamine) is just feels so irresistible because our brain is wired that way. But just as you are able to form a habit (addiction) to it, the steps also can be reversed. You can form a habit not to watch it. If you just rely on your will power, though, it will be like fighting Muhammad Ali after living like a couch potato for [time you have been watching porn]. I know because I have read numerous books to help me get out, and my father teaches at colleges and consult people who are on addiction. You can be a pastor, professor, or an athlete with a great will power but more likely than not you will lose. The only solution I found is to &lt;a href="parental-control.html"&gt;try to block it off completely.&lt;/a&gt; You will never get it right the first time, but don't give up and keep on blocking the Internet. You might not be able to block it right away, but the whole point is to make it as difficult as possible. Your brain is wired to do thing that are easy and get brainwashed easily by visual contents. The moment you lost and feel defeated and guilty, is the best time to devise a strategy for the next victory. It took me about five years, but only because I did not get my strategy right the first time. Once I had it down, as it I found a way to block porn and not everything else I need, it was about a three month long battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I am glad that I have tackled this early on in my life, because things are going to get more complicated. I have not tried to do self-parental control on my phone because I have not felt the need to, but I figure things could be a bit more troublesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't stop it yourself, you will be forced to stop and you will be sorry. The other solution that the professor in the video mentions is to become erectilely dysfunctional. As a human being, I really want you to have a happy marriage. As a fellow society member, I really do not want to pay for your problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not found any source that says masturbation causes health problem. That is up to your philosophical / religious beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you have an idea that your girlfriend is your porn substitute, I would like you to consider otherwise for a long-term happiness. In college, my friends almost convinced by arguing that I need physical compatibility for a happy marriage. There is some truth to it, but it is not the complete picture. &lt;a href="http://www.artofmanliness.com/2013/07/01/how-delaying-intimacy-can-benefit-your-relationship/"&gt;Our sex is much more psychological than physical when it comes to marriage.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="security"></category><category term="psychology"></category><category term="habit"></category></entry><entry><title>My thoughts and predictions on bitcoin</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/bitcoin-rant.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-03-30T09:45:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-03-30T09:45:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-03-30:/bitcoin-rant.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I never owned any bitcoin. I read about it and understand its technical achievements, but I do not see it replacing our current currency system. For our intend and purposes, lets say bitcoin's market price becomes somewhat stable and it has been all mined up. Even at this point, the government has no way of tracking its transactions and therefore cannot back it up or protect any of its financial transactions. Well, that is the whole point of the cryptocurrrency. It cannot be used to provide FDIC insurance ($250,000 per account per person in case of bank run-ons). So …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I never owned any bitcoin. I read about it and understand its technical achievements, but I do not see it replacing our current currency system. For our intend and purposes, lets say bitcoin's market price becomes somewhat stable and it has been all mined up. Even at this point, the government has no way of tracking its transactions and therefore cannot back it up or protect any of its financial transactions. Well, that is the whole point of the cryptocurrrency. It cannot be used to provide FDIC insurance ($250,000 per account per person in case of bank run-ons). So for typical people, it provides no protection at all. So it cannot be embraced by and for the popular mass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that leaves the rich and the ultra rich. Surely, they need a system in which they could transfer money discretely for their lobbying and money laundering, right? And with the increasing disparity between rich and poor, it just makes sense to have a magic stash for these people. Barring the possibility that bitcoin replaces the currency, could it find its usefulness here? Maybe. But I see this less than likely to happen, even with a much safer personal vault (e.g. Trucrypt Container variant). Because, it is just not an economically stable vehicle for storing wealth, a.k.a. the perceived value of one's labor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now bitcoin is miles ahead of its competitor in terms of &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/1dul2m/anyone_else_see_all_these_new_copycat_cryptos_as/c9tzuca"&gt;"market cap, popularity, network strength, real economy (products &amp;amp; services), trading volume, wallet software"&lt;/a&gt;. But believe or not, cryptocurrency will be replicated in the future with ease and there will be much more demand to do so if the bitcoin has reached it mining limit. There is no entity to regulate replication for cryptocurrency, and the government has no incentive to do so when it cannot control it or protect it. If you allowed people to print their set of money, just because \$100 bills have been all printed out, that does not prevent people from printing \$49 bills or \$4 bills or 2 cent coins. You see LiteCoin, DogeCoin, etc keep popping out. This trend will go on and the entire cryptocurrency will collapse in economic sense (but not disappear). It is not viable for people to store their wealth in cryptocurrency, especially so if you are super rich and have got more to lose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryptocrurency can be useful though, if it can be paired with services provided by companies like Facebook, Wikipedia, Google, Quora, Stackoverflow - for rewarding people for doing something that a computer or machine is unable to do. (e.g. reCaptcha) If someone asks a question and the computer is unable to answer it, the person who answers it can be awarded. The cryptocurrency can then be used to ask another question. This will fuel innovation and change how our economy works. But until this system comes along, bitcoin is just a prototype. The company or an entity who creates this system and provide services will come up with his/her own cryptocurrency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, cyptocurrency will be like collectible cards: Magic, Pocketmon, YugiOh, NBA, NFL, or MLB cards. Some people will want it, like it, trade it, sell it, buy it, or barter it, but its circulation will be limited to one group (like playing cards collectors) and its valuation will be tied to the government backed currency (because most people value protection over privacy). As for me, I don't want to be that kid again who collects cards or coins because it is 'cool'. I still regret trading my lego pieces for Looney Tunes cards back when I was five. I've learn my lesson the "hard" way. And I feel really good about writing this article, because I had a strong impulse to buy an ASIC bitcoin miner before and I knew it wasn't a logical choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haz a limited-edition Pocketmon-Coinz, do you want to trade it for your college tuition money? You are getting a great deal. A greeaaat deal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Using bitcoin to fix DDoS problem? I don't think so&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I want to point out is &lt;a href="http://www.cdixon.org/2014/03/15/stored-hashcash/"&gt;Chris Dixon's idea on using cryptocurrency to prevent network congestion.&lt;/a&gt;. I do not think bitcoin is the way to solve DDoS problem because most problematic DDoS attacks are not initiated by users who are hefty about their internet usage, but rather it is by their hacked computers that triggers the attack simultaneously with other zombie machines at the same time. One network communication is cheap enough that once the attack has happened, the user will not notice that much difference in their billing statements that they were a part of the attack. Even if the cost of network transmission was proportionally expensive to the bandwidth demanded, the distributed cost will make it seem like nothing to benign individuals who are a part of the attack. I believe money (supply/demand) is not the problem here. I am criticizing something here without giving an alternative solution, which goes against my own philosophy about criticizing, but I just had to throw it out there and put some water on bitcoin hype. Chris, by some chance if you are reading this, I like your all of your other articles, man. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="finance"></category><category term="rant"></category></entry><entry><title>My Simplified Investment Guide for Retirement</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/retirement-investment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-03-29T01:31:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-03-29T01:31:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-03-29:/retirement-investment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have at least a dozen books on investment and for me, they boil down to the summary below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary Chart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; |                     | Roth 401K | Roth IRA           | HSA           | 401K              |
 | Contributions       | Taxed     | Taxed              | Not Taxed     | Not Taxed         |
 | Lowers AGI          | No        | No                 | Yes           | Yes               |
 | Withdrawals         | Not Taxed | Not Taxed          | Not for med.  | Taxed             |
 | Limit (/&amp;gt;50)        | 17.5/23k  | 5.5/6.5k           | 33/65k        | 52k/57.5k (Taxed) |
 | Income Limits (S/M) | None      | 112-127/178-188k   | None          | None              |
 | Distribution        | 59.5      | 59.5               | 65            | 59.5              |
 | Required Minimum    | 70.5      | None               | None          | 70.5              |
 | Maintained by       | Employer  | Self               | Self/Employer | Employer          |
 | Early Withdrawals   | 10%       | 10 …&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have at least a dozen books on investment and for me, they boil down to the summary below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary Chart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; |                     | Roth 401K | Roth IRA           | HSA           | 401K              |
 | Contributions       | Taxed     | Taxed              | Not Taxed     | Not Taxed         |
 | Lowers AGI          | No        | No                 | Yes           | Yes               |
 | Withdrawals         | Not Taxed | Not Taxed          | Not for med.  | Taxed             |
 | Limit (/&amp;gt;50)        | 17.5/23k  | 5.5/6.5k           | 33/65k        | 52k/57.5k (Taxed) |
 | Income Limits (S/M) | None      | 112-127/178-188k   | None          | None              |
 | Distribution        | 59.5      | 59.5               | 65            | 59.5              |
 | Required Minimum    | 70.5      | None               | None          | 70.5              |
 | Maintained by       | Employer  | Self               | Self/Employer | Employer          |
 | Early Withdrawals   | 10%       | 10% non-prin &amp;lt; 5yr | 20%           | 10%               |
 | Special Note        |           | 60 days loaning    |               | CA Muni Bonds     |
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;The Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay off the debt first, exception being your student loan or family loan which can have a lower rate of interest than a typical investment plan (~7% on average, ~5% conservative).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any employer contribution is free money, but don't forego 401k contribution even if there isn't any.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are young and expect your income level will be higher in the future, max out Roth contribution first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take advantage of IRA if you think you will be a top-income earner one day, because you won't be even have this option anymore when you are the top income level (~97 percentile for single, 90 for joint, see the numbers in the above chart).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose Non-Roth option if you are old and/or are pessimistic about your career, or if you think the tax will be lower in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have extra money, try to invest in your self-growth: especially in your education, career, or business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you still have money left for no immediate use, then go for a brokerage account. I recommend any index funds instead of tax-saving vehicles at this point, because you need some liquidity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Health Savings Account as an extra tax efficient vehicle. It is less flexible than IRA, the penalty is higher if you withdraw early. I would only recommend it if you know you have imminent or foresesable medical expenses. A good bookeeping skill required for all the medical expenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For any conversion or withdrawal, do it when you are in a lower tax bracket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since I take a more risk in my retirement accounts, I take a safe approach for my short-term savings. Certificate of Deposit (CD) or Bonds are recommended by most people for short-term savings, but these people are not looking hard enough. With inflation, you could actually end up losing money. Look for High-Yield Savings Accounts (the rate might be the same, but it is more liquid) online, or High-yield Checking Accounts that might be available at a local Credit Union.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credit cards offers and deals so far has given me better returns (for my time) than their points system. I keep them around for my credit score.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribution deadline is April 15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you feel like you are saving too much into your retirement accounts, you should think otherwise. There are exceptions to 10% IRS penalty called &lt;a href="https://www.fidelity.com/viewpoints/retirement/taking-money-early"&gt;Substantially Equal Periodic Payment (SEPP)&lt;/a&gt;. You can tap into your retirement accounts as early as when you are 35 years old. &lt;a href="http://www.bankrate.com/calculators/retirement/72-t-distribution-calculator.aspx"&gt;The are three methods of calculation for the distribution amount.&lt;/a&gt; Don't do SEPP on Roth though, as it gets taxed as income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to avoid it penalty is when you buy a house for the first time. If you (and your spouse) have not owned a home for two years, you can &lt;a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/f/firsttimehomebuyer.asp"&gt;contribute&lt;/a&gt; up to 10,000 per person (up to $20,000 with your spouse's contribution) to your "home" (principal place of residence).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think trying to beat the market is not worth your time, but should you decide to put your money into the hands of fund managers, go for small cap equity. Here is an excellent article titled &lt;a href="http://cuffelinks.com.au/index-versus-active-nobel-prize-professors-cant-agree/"&gt;"Index versus active? Nobel Prize professors can't agree"&lt;/a&gt; that gave me the insight. Past performance is not an indicator of future performance, but I think it makes sense that fund managers could leverage their connections and knowledge to make significant gains in small cap companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invest early and focus on savings rate rather than making smart moves. Keep things simple and forget about it for 360 days in a year. But if you like learning about this stuff, go nuts like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you read through investment forum threads skim through the contents that does not have any number or chart, otherwise you might be filling up your brain with unnecessary sob stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;IRA == Emergency Funds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is pretty much for those who have maxed out their 401k contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to use Roth IRA as your emergency fund, contribute to it directly. This allows you to withdraw the principal at any time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then do direct contribution to traditional 401k and then do the rollover, but note that this money will not be liquid for 5 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you cumulate it, you can use it for the first-time home purchase for you or your wife, your children, or your ancestors, but only once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roth IRA withdrawal on the contribution is exempt from tax on earning if &lt;a href="http://www.kitces.com/blog/understanding-the-two-5-year-rules-for-roth-ira-contributions-and-conversions/"&gt;the account has been open for more than 5 years.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use IRA as an emergency fund but if you want to keep the tax savings, you have to put the money back in 60 days or 120 days for exceptions outlined below. &lt;a href="http://www.bankrate.com/finance/retirement/rule-allows-penalty-free-ira-withdrawal.aspx"&gt;This can be done once every 12 months.&lt;/a&gt;, but this is risky and not recommended. (Stock Tanks -&amp;gt; Recession -&amp;gt; Lose Job -&amp;gt; Tab Emergency Fund -&amp;gt; Sell stocks at the worst time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/personalfinance/comments/1xqzhw/am_i_putting_too_much_into_my_401k_and_ira/cfe7oim"&gt;Rollover taxed 401k to Roth IRA&lt;/a&gt; as the last resort for tax shelter. &lt;a href="http://moneyover55.about.com/od/401ks/a/2013-401-k-Contribution-Limits.htm"&gt;It is the least efficient but has the highest limit.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fool.com/money/allaboutiras/allaboutiras01.htm"&gt;Withdrawals that does not incur penalty before the age of 59.5&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRA owner's disability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRA owner's death.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are a series of "substantially equal periodic payments" made over the life expectancy of the IRA owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unreimbursed medical expenses that exceed 7 1/2% of adjusted gross income (AGI).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;medical insurance premiums after the IRA owner has received unemployment compensation for more than 12 weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the costs of a first-time home purchase (subject to a lifetime limit of $10,000).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for the qualified expenses of higher education for the IRA owner and/or eligible family members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;back taxes because of an Internal Revenue Service levy placed against the IRA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First Time Home Buyer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with all the rules above, the withdrawal will be in the order of
1. Maximum amount of principal I have put in directly. (e.g. ~$27500 for 5 years)
2. Up to $10,000 on the earnings
3. Any contribution, (not earnings) that is over 5 years old
4. Start paying 10% income tax on the rest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A little extra - Health Savings Account&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really a healthy person's insurance, and I am debating whether I should commit to maxing out, because of the bookkeeping I have to do on my medical expenses and the inflexibility in transfer of funds. I just trying to convince myself that this will force me to have a good financial habits and skils, which might become necessary as my investment grows. But I worry that it might be eating too much of my time.
Here is the best infographic/summary I found on the web. &lt;a href="http://www.madfientist.com/hsa/"&gt;Read this first.&lt;/a&gt;
Here is &lt;a href="http://20somethingfinance.com/best-hsa-account/"&gt;a small comparison chart for HSA providers&lt;/a&gt;. Some big banks like Chase and Bank of America also offer HSA, but you'd be surprised to find a bigger fees (than alternatives) when you search deeper. So my recommendation is &lt;a href="http://www.hsabank.com/"&gt;HSA bank&lt;/a&gt; because of their low monthly fee for low-balance accounts and then it gets waived after ~$5000 in the account. Some attractive investment options are provided through TD Ameritrade.
This is the best tax shelter after you have maxed out on your investment account. It might be THE best if you know your medical expenses will be high, because your contribution to HSA via payroll deduction is pre-tax and gives you savings on your FICA taxes - Social Security and Medical, if your employer does it for you. There is a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Health_savings_account#Deposits"&gt;limit to the contributions&lt;/a&gt;, however.
Regarding the tax issue (e.g. the company offers HRA, but not HSA, so you don't get FICA savings, etc), your best guide is &lt;a href="http://www.healthsavingsaccount-hsa.com/FAQ.htm"&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot double dip on HRA and HSA. Couldn't find a source online, but I confirmed it with a financial advisor at my credit union. Don't try because IRS know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some more strategy for Californians who get taxed on HRA at the state level: Invest in Treasury Bonds or TIPS to avoid paying California Tax. Your overall return will be similar to your other investment account due since this is going to be no tax, low return investment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not worry about making voluntary contribution, because &lt;a href="http://www.opm.gov/healthcare-insurance/healthcare/health-savings-accounts/frequently-asked-questions/"&gt;they are tax-deductable.&lt;/a&gt;. So there is no requirement for it to be payroll deduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Picking Portfolio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For your portfolio, &lt;a href="http://www.bogleheads.org/wiki/Principles_of_tax-efficient_fund_placement#Step_1:_Categorize_your_portfolio.27s_tax_efficiency"&gt;choose a mixture as you see fit, but watch out for tax and fees&lt;/a&gt; You could throw darts on a list of funds, but reading some news about the interest rates, the fiscal policy, the monetary policy and the world economy should help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be more conservative and have more bonds as you get older.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal Strategy (subject to change)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roth 401k, Roth IRA, HSA, 401k rolled over to Roth IRA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any excessive money / windfall / real estate opportunties -&amp;gt; mortgage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="investment"></category><category term="finance"></category><category term="retirement"></category></entry><entry><title>Having a great conversation is like playing a great tennis game</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/conversation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-03-03T09:38:00-08:00</published><updated>2014-03-03T09:38:00-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-03-03:/conversation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A great relationship starts with a great conversation, and frankly I am not a great conversation holder by nature. My brother used to get so mad at me for asking boring, straightforward questions that seem to lead no where. But when I think of a conversation as a tennis game, it makes things a bit easier for me to be more sociable person. At the basic level, a conversation is compromised of questioning and answering. Likewise, a tennis game is compromised of serving and returning.  Here is the set of rules I keep in my head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tennis =&amp;gt; Conversation
Server =&amp;gt; Questioner …&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A great relationship starts with a great conversation, and frankly I am not a great conversation holder by nature. My brother used to get so mad at me for asking boring, straightforward questions that seem to lead no where. But when I think of a conversation as a tennis game, it makes things a bit easier for me to be more sociable person. At the basic level, a conversation is compromised of questioning and answering. Likewise, a tennis game is compromised of serving and returning.  Here is the set of rules I keep in my head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tennis =&amp;gt; Conversation
Server =&amp;gt; Questioner / Listerner / Conversation Lead
Receiver =&amp;gt; Talker
Return =&amp;gt; Talking
No return =&amp;gt; A terse response, deflective response, or no response
Objective =&amp;gt; 1. Try to have fun 2. Try to keep the score as close as the other person.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When you first start out a conversation with a stranger, you have a no clue about where to begin, so you ask a question that anyone could relate: family, friends, school, pet, sports, weather, or traveling. If the question gets returned with any sort of enthusiasm, great! Every time a person talks, it is an opportunity to make things more interesting. If you ask a question or talk about something but it does not get returned with similar enthusiasm, you have one more chance to start a new topic (hopefully a safer, easier topic). If the second try gets you no where, it is time to change the role and let the other person take the lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Speed =&amp;gt; pace of the conversation, difficulty of the topic (Intellectual)
Range =&amp;gt; Scope of the subject, length of the conversation (Sociable)
Spin =&amp;gt; Private / Tricky subject (Nuance / Reading the body-language)
You can go for the edge shots and risk crossing the line. But that can be exciting too ;) (flirting)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can use own description here - as long as you have some sort of a game plan. But "Speed" is something the people have difficulty adjusting up. "Range" is how quickly the subject changes. Some people's mind just like to jump around or get lost in the story they are telling. "Spin" requires more attention, but the unexpected/unnoticeable changes could provide fun challenges. And finally if you are "aiming for the edge", I call it flirting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no such thing as a social ladder and "sociability" is a relative metric, but you can kind of tell by asking yourself - "How much fun are you having right now?"
There are three scenarios, in the ascending order of typical "fun-ness":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You are more sociable than that person&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Andy Rodick gave you a 170 mph top-spin serve on every round, you probably would be impressed, but would not have a very enjoyable tennis game. So it is time for you to put yourself in the other person's shoe and put your social skill to work. Yes it can be unpleasant to be in this position and you might even feel like you are wasting your time, but don't be cocky. Go with the attitude that there is always something to learn - a humble approach opens doors in life. You never know what's going to happen in the future. Yes you can dupe the other person in this position, but you never know when you will fall victim to your own wit. If you play with the law of power, it will play you. I recommend reading &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/48-Laws-Power-Robert-Greene/dp/0140280197"&gt;The 48 Laws of Power&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The other person is more sociable than you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you do not need to try too hard to impress the other person, especially if you do not know that person well. Also asking serial questions or speaking in monologue is a good sign that the conversation is getting no where. Let the other person take the lead and you follow. Sometimes just listening, nodding head, and making eye contacts are enough to let the other person adjust to you. Try playing by the rules (social-convention) and not be swayed by the other people's style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You guys are on the same page:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ask anyone which is the best tennis game they have seen, it is usually between two very competitive players. Likewise, if you ask anyone which is the best tennis game they played, it is usually with someone who was just as good as they were. You can be yourself here and take more risky moves if you are comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an imaginary tennis ball coming out of the other person's mouth.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="relationship"></category></entry><entry><title>My Choice of Hardware</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/gadgets.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-02-13T01:53:00-08:00</published><updated>2014-02-13T01:53:00-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-02-13:/gadgets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My choice of hardware is typically based on the software. But there are other reasons too. I tend to overlook the price tag if possible, because I use my devices often enough that the productivity is actually more bigger factor in my choices, but I actually found that the most productive combination I found tends to be economical as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Phone + Camera | Nexus 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock Android Experience all the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tablet | iPad2 Wifi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the only Apple product I use. Its purpose is to replace paper. All my music sheets and books are stored there. None of the Android …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My choice of hardware is typically based on the software. But there are other reasons too. I tend to overlook the price tag if possible, because I use my devices often enough that the productivity is actually more bigger factor in my choices, but I actually found that the most productive combination I found tends to be economical as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Phone + Camera | Nexus 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock Android Experience all the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tablet | iPad2 Wifi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the only Apple product I use. Its purpose is to replace paper. All my music sheets and books are stored there. None of the Android iPad-killer actually lived up to its title, but more importantly, I like its accessibility options (test-to-speech, inverse colors). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Laptop | Dell Latitude and Lenovo Thinkpad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business laptops are well-constructed and the warranty services you receive are much more pleasant than the consumer-level warranty. I prefer U-lines of Intel series because they do not get too hot. The temperature is important because I found laptop's keyboard and touchpad combination more ergonomic than any setup. The PageUp and PageDown keys' positions, dock station, extended battery and onsite warranty are my requirements for a laptop. I invert my screen's color so the color gamut also does not bother me too much. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Server | Pogoplug E2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is faster than raspberry pi, 1/20th fraction of cost of Synology. I got this for $15 including shipping through Adorama. It serves my purpose right with ArchLinux installed on it. It also makes me feel good about saving energy and going green. I also do not mind spending a lot of time on servers, because it is a learning experience that is applicable to other places. Right now it is serving as a network storage off-site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;External Hard drive | Seagate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no really a winner in the spinning disk world. Every company's product fail at one point. Seagate is cheaper than Western Digital though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Abandoned Devices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Media streaming devices (e.g. Roku): I returned it after using it for two weeks. The inconsistent connection, and lack of control, and other restrictions makes it better to either watch straight to a computer, or just connect HDMI cable to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="best"></category></entry><entry><title>How your perception of negotiation could hurt you</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/negotiation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-12-18T09:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2013-12-18T09:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-12-18:/negotiation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Book-taught negotiation skill and in-practice negotiation are different ball-game. The book you buy from Amazon, despite its wisdom and anecdotes, fails to address the context that you are in. Yes, it is good to read one, but knowing the value of what you can offer and your alternatives or calculating the risks on a spot is a skill that is difficult to acquire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So no, I can't teach you to acquire that skill, but just tell you my experience. First time out of college, I called for a 6-figure income. I high balled quite bit and I thought the company …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Book-taught negotiation skill and in-practice negotiation are different ball-game. The book you buy from Amazon, despite its wisdom and anecdotes, fails to address the context that you are in. Yes, it is good to read one, but knowing the value of what you can offer and your alternatives or calculating the risks on a spot is a skill that is difficult to acquire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So no, I can't teach you to acquire that skill, but just tell you my experience. First time out of college, I called for a 6-figure income. I high balled quite bit and I thought the company would negotiate with me for the salary I was actually expecting. The end result was that the negotiation was dismissed right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, in another company, I did not negotiate. I just took what they gave me. I made the meeting end in less than 5 minutes. And in the offer letter, I was a given a raise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, there are a lot of details I am leaving out, but one thing was clearly different in the second case: I was interested in proving myself worthy to HR rather than showing my greed. And proving yourself worthy is not something you can pull in 5 minutes. I have already built the reputation through other people before entering that room for negotiation. By not negotiating, I demonstrated the passion for the company. Sometimes less words speak louder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think you've lost in negotiation. Ask yourself if that is really the case. Asking that very question and finding the answer within yourself may be more important than the negotiation itself. Negotiation, in most cases, do not have a clear starting point and end point. Keep that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>What does it mean to "have no life"?</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/have-no-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-17T10:38:00-08:00</published><updated>2013-11-17T10:38:00-08:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-11-17:/have-no-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I began to hear this term since college. From my experience, it was used as an excuse for something or just a attempt to gain sympathy from peers (who doesn't want to play victim?). I was reading a post by an investment banker on Quora who confessed to become wealthy at the cost of having no life. He was trying to send a message that money is not everything, but that got me thinking... do I have a life? I do not watch TV or video games, but the only place I go on weekends is church. Otherwise, I just …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I began to hear this term since college. From my experience, it was used as an excuse for something or just a attempt to gain sympathy from peers (who doesn't want to play victim?). I was reading a post by an investment banker on Quora who confessed to become wealthy at the cost of having no life. He was trying to send a message that money is not everything, but that got me thinking... do I have a life? I do not watch TV or video games, but the only place I go on weekends is church. Otherwise, I just work or study or read articles on the web. I do things instead of sitting idly somewhere or force myself to meet people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For personal questions, I think Yahoo Answer is the best place. Answers are simple, direct, and suited for everyone. &lt;a href="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20120122143349AAKjbz8"&gt;One person said&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;To me &amp;quot;HAVING LIFE&amp;quot; means, being contended with one&amp;#39;s life, having self respect and dignity, having values and morals, and not interested to control, interfere and bother other&amp;#39;s life or jealous of others. So even a poor person earning just to live have all those, then he has life.
While &amp;quot;Having no life&amp;quot; means, the one who is not contended with his/her own life, has no self esteem and has no respect for self and others and have low values and morals. Even a rich with relationships and family/friends doesn&amp;#39;t have above, then he/she has no life
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here additional things that make me look like I do not have life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not travel, but make exceptions for people I have not met for a long time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not try to get laid. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not try to make my life seem interesting to others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are things that I do so I can have a life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I provide people tech support without any expectation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have few people me in my contact list, so I can get back to them right away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not have Facebook. I do not have even have that many friends. But I recently celebrated my friend's wedding half way around the world. I could not go there myself, but I had a relative you was glad to show up on my behalf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I try to be committed to people I see today, rather than a year ago.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like to celebrate everyone's birthday together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I live in a protective cell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My family loves me to death, because I do what they ask of me and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not know if I work hard, but recently I was working late one night and my co-worker told me to go home because I look rest of the team look bad. So I just take my work laptop home now. If you think you are working HARD, you are not enjoying what you are doing. You should go to work dancing. Your work should be a playground. It should be a place where you get self-actualization and self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But most important of all, your family is the indicator of a healthy relationship. Go watch &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0389860/"&gt;click&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0038650/"&gt;It's a Wonderful Life&lt;/a&gt;. If you have a outstanding family relationship (that is built on a moral ground, not life mafia), you have life in my book. Don't let anyone tell you otherwise. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="lifestyle"></category></entry><entry><title>Learning Chinese</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/learning-chinese.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-30T07:24:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-10-30T07:24:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-10-30:/learning-chinese.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Why learn Mandarin?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ihs.com/info/ecc/a/economic-predictions-2013.aspx"&gt;China's economy is gaining momentum&lt;/a&gt; and there are a lot of people who will use Mandarin.
Frankly, I studied Spanish for four years and I still do not think I do not have positive ROI of my time. I managed to get better services and find my way in Los Angeles downtown with my rusty Spanish, but I never had to speak the language in social settings or at work. When I was in college I met a lot of Chinese people and I felt left out whenever I joined their social group. Because East Asia countries …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Why learn Mandarin?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ihs.com/info/ecc/a/economic-predictions-2013.aspx"&gt;China's economy is gaining momentum&lt;/a&gt; and there are a lot of people who will use Mandarin.
Frankly, I studied Spanish for four years and I still do not think I do not have positive ROI of my time. I managed to get better services and find my way in Los Angeles downtown with my rusty Spanish, but I never had to speak the language in social settings or at work. When I was in college I met a lot of Chinese people and I felt left out whenever I joined their social group. Because East Asia countries are very ethnocentric, it is really difficult to build strong bonds in relationship without knowing the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was the president of Chinese Language Club in high school, but my effort to learn Mandarin never lasted long. So now I am going for long-term (10-years) and no-pressure approach. My current setup is:
&lt;em&gt; &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ichi2.anki"&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt; - vocabulary. There are decks with speech too.
&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pleco.chinesesystem"&gt;Pleco&lt;/a&gt; - input writing came free with the promotion and I paid for the stroke order diagram. It is really money well spent. I am going to for traditional characters because my plan is to learn Mandarin over next 10 years. 
* &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Learn-Mandarin-Fluenz-supplemental-Podcasts/dp/B00310UXQW/"&gt;Learn Mandarin: Fluenz Mandarin 1+2+3 with supplemental Audio CDs and Podcasts&lt;/a&gt; - I think I learn better with female instructor. I kid. Their emphasis on typing the intonation after listening, encouraging to memorize the dialog are big pluses. You get the feeling of using a start-up company's beta software in comparison to say, Rosetta Stone, but the product lives up to Amazon.com's user rating in terms of knowledge retention. It is pricey though. See if you snag one on eBay.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Resources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mandarinposter.com/resources/simplified-radicals-list-free-printable-reference/"&gt;Learn radicals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.learnchineseez.com/read-write/simplified/index.php"&gt;common characters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read chinese ([Chinese Haacks][http://chinesehacks.com/])&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch children's cartoon &lt;a href="http://so.letv.com/comic/49702.html"&gt;喜洋洋与灰太狼&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch Chinese TV shows (&lt;a href="http://sugoideas.com"&gt;sugoideas.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href="http://www.imqq.com/"&gt;QQ&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="renren.com"&gt;RenRen&lt;/a&gt; - to communicate with Chinese people and practice in real world settings. Most Chinese people I met graciously responded in English when I could not continue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Chinese News (&lt;a href="http://www.sohu.com/"&gt;Sohu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/zhongwen/simp/"&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://us.weibo.com/gb"&gt;weibo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Chinese search engine (&lt;a href="http://www.baidu.com/"&gt;Baidu&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hire Chinese tutor and read a book together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Programs:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.translate&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Google translate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.embermitre.hanping.app.reader.pro"&gt;Hanping for Android&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pleco-chinese-dictionary/id341922306?mt=8"&gt;Pleco for iOS&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supposedly &lt;a href="http://www.theworldofchinese.com/2013/04/ocr-app-faceoff-can-your-phone-read-chinese/"&gt;Hanping &amp;gt; Pleco&lt;/a&gt;, but you be the judge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://chinese.fluentu.com/courses/#popular"&gt;Fluent U&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="skritter.com"&gt;skritter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/skritter-chinese/id520277126?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8"&gt;Skritter Chinese in iOS&lt;/a&gt; for writing practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.quora.com/Learning-Chinese-1/Whats-the-best-way-for-an-American-born-Chinese-person-to-relearn-Chinese"&gt;http://www.quora.com/Learning-Chinese-1/Whats-the-best-way-for-an-American-born-Chinese-person-to-relearn-Chinese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.quora.com/Chinese-language/What-is-the-best-way-to-learn-Chinese-1"&gt;http://www.quora.com/Chinese-language/What-is-the-best-way-to-learn-Chinese-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://confusedlaowai.com/2012/09/9-essential-digital-tools-chinese-learners/"&gt;http://confusedlaowai.com/2012/09/9-essential-digital-tools-chinese-learners/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="language"></category><category term="chinese"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Single Monitor rules</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/single-monitor.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-11T01:14:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-10-11T01:14:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-10-11:/single-monitor.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;No matter how good of a peripheral vision you have, you cannot possibly focus on entire surface of 24" monitor. So why then would you want a big monitor or even multiple monitors? Because you have a less-than-optimal setup where turning your head is faster than switching tasks with your hands. If you want to be an expert, you got to become a shortcut-foo master. Just like an expert pianists do not rely on their eyes but their senses, your computer and you must become one via keyboard. Muscle memory is much more efficient than a computer. I have written …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;No matter how good of a peripheral vision you have, you cannot possibly focus on entire surface of 24" monitor. So why then would you want a big monitor or even multiple monitors? Because you have a less-than-optimal setup where turning your head is faster than switching tasks with your hands. If you want to be an expert, you got to become a shortcut-foo master. Just like an expert pianists do not rely on their eyes but their senses, your computer and you must become one via keyboard. Muscle memory is much more efficient than a computer. I have written about &lt;a href="windows-management.html"&gt;my shortcut setup in another article&lt;/a&gt; and with that setup, you should be fine with just one monitor. You should be able to switch to tasks using muscle memory rather than twitching your head like a dove. I have used multiple monitor before, but with the frequency of my task switching, I get sores all over my neck, and my irritating neck ruins my mood and patience to get my work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screen resolution, size went up and the price went down over the years, but for me the ratio comes up as a requirement. This is because there are a limit number of models that defy the conventional 16:9 widescreen display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently using Dell UltraSharp 24" IPS panel which has 1920x1200 resolution. That extra 180 vertical pixel comes very handy. I recommend it wholeheartedly. I think review stars will mean more to you than my endorsement. I found &amp;gt;4 stars everywhere and I think it is best one for the specification I am looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is better than to invest money on a side-kick laptop that you could keep you productive while your main computer is busy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>Life Hacking for Thinkers</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/lifehack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-19T11:50:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-19T11:50:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-09-19:/lifehack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="pages/aboutme.html"&gt;aboutme page&lt;/a&gt;, I say I am a lifehacker graduate. There is a profound meaning in those words. Back in 2008, when lifehacker.com was gaining a greater public attraction, I was there. I subscribed to their RSS feed and went through most of the articles for almost three years. I became more knowledgeable and wiser with each article, but it also cost me a great deal of time. Now their articles seem recycled to me and now I see that they are not the most efficient ways to get things done. (&lt;a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/10/todont.html"&gt;Jeff Atwood also complains about their todo …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="pages/aboutme.html"&gt;aboutme page&lt;/a&gt;, I say I am a lifehacker graduate. There is a profound meaning in those words. Back in 2008, when lifehacker.com was gaining a greater public attraction, I was there. I subscribed to their RSS feed and went through most of the articles for almost three years. I became more knowledgeable and wiser with each article, but it also cost me a great deal of time. Now their articles seem recycled to me and now I see that they are not the most efficient ways to get things done. (&lt;a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/10/todont.html"&gt;Jeff Atwood also complains about their todo app recommendation&lt;/a&gt;. He apparently uses his &lt;a href="http://lifehacker.com/5950386/im-jeff-atwood-founder-of-stack-exchange-and-this-is-how-i-work"&gt;brain for his to-do list manager&lt;/a&gt;. I use gVim for that.) Anyway, at first, I filtered their articles with Google Reader Filter userscript. Now I filter them using Yahoo Pipe. I personally filter about 10 articles each day from the filtered feed, and read about 2 articles seriously. I have grown up and now I found home at Stackoverflow. Quora is fun to read, but it is hard to justify the time I spend there. To conclude, I still see some gems on lifehacker.com and I still search through their articles and comments when I need a recommendation on something. The community they have can be very helpful and insightful, but they do not take you to the next level of technical savviness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I am continue writing for this blog, I began to wonder, "Am I writing a sequel to lifehacker.com?" I think I am. I am also focusing on aspects that matter and enticed me to lifehacker.com in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Desktop Customization is a waste of time</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/desktop-customization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-15T11:16:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-15T11:16:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-09-15:/desktop-customization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are designs that are useful, and there are designs that are unnecessary. When desiging something, let each element have a purpose and serve it well. Making a "in-between" design might make it a good marketing-gimick, but it will end up being a waste of time. Yes there is an exception to this rule, like a big phone, but I think it is very difficult to make the case for desktop customization. I would even argue that desktop customization as a harem of design (notorious MySpace customization back in 2007 fall under this category). It's flashy and desriable, but it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are designs that are useful, and there are designs that are unnecessary. When desiging something, let each element have a purpose and serve it well. Making a "in-between" design might make it a good marketing-gimick, but it will end up being a waste of time. Yes there is an exception to this rule, like a big phone, but I think it is very difficult to make the case for desktop customization. I would even argue that desktop customization as a harem of design (notorious MySpace customization back in 2007 fall under this category). It's flashy and desriable, but it is often morally wrong because it eats up your time and brain power for no good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Weather&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always found morning sky to be a better indicator than the cute looking ones on PDAs, Desktops, etc. If I really wanted to know about the weather, I would just make a browser shortcut so that I can see the detailed report on it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desktop Background Image&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am curious how much time you spend staring at that image. The time I spent looking at my desktop accounts for less than 1% of my computer usage. And if I am looking at it, it is because I need to see the icons on my desktop. I do not want the desktop image to interfere with the view of icons on there, so I keep it pretty monotone. 
syn match myExCapitalWords +\&amp;lt;\w&lt;em&gt;[A-Z]\K&lt;/em&gt;&gt;+ contains=@NoSpell &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hardware stats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, this can be useful, but still unnecessary. I could think of a three scenario when looking at these numbers: 1) Your hardware load is low - you lost a second of your life needlessly and you move on. 2) Your hardware load is high - you need to figure out why, you either pullout &lt;code&gt;Windows Task Manager&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt; to kill the troublemaker. 3) You are trying to see whether your latest installation or action is causing a spike in the process. I could easily tell if my system is under load by the latency I experience, when that happens, I pull out WTM or htop right away. It gives me all the details I need right away. Once again I am better off without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Custom Icons / No icons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay it might give you that 'Zen' feeling as you stare at that uncluttered page. I use web browser's new tab page for this purpose. I do not need to customize this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Newsfeed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy reading introduction of articles, this is for you. It's not for me. RSS readers are much better optimized for reading experience and saving your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Todo-list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just use vim for this. Much faster to find what you need and edit it on the spot, in a vim way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only real optimization I do is the color scheme, because darker color is much easier on my eyes. But even here, I just use a theme someone created, so it is a one-click deal. I do not look for other themes because the current one serves its purpose well. Another exception I would take is a vocabulary card on your desktop. I say exception, because if I am ever looking at my desktop, I am in a middle of doing something. I really do not want something trivial to make me lose focus. I have done something like this on my terminal with GRE words, but it was not that very helpful. Whenever you look at some notification, you brain is making a context-switch. And we know that context-switch is not a cheap operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So all in all, I would say desktop customization could create more distraction than improve productivity, and that defeats the purpose of a good design. I am a type of a person who finds a cartoon on an exam, for example, distracting, so I am an extremist. But the takeaway here is that do not get jealous when someone has a flashy desktop or an office space. Simpler is better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="design"></category><category term="complaints"></category></entry><entry><title>Companies that raised red flags during my interview process</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/companies-red-flag.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-11T09:03:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-11T09:03:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-09-11:/companies-red-flag.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey you should take my experience with a grain of salt, but these are the rules I will bind by in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honesty is one of the requirements in the job description: No one can test honesty, so listing it on a job description is kind of funny thing. I found these companies to be less transparent, actually. I guess they need more honest people because they are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot get any information on the company's salary range: if a company does does not ask for your desired/minimum salary, they will not pay you well, treat you …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey you should take my experience with a grain of salt, but these are the rules I will bind by in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honesty is one of the requirements in the job description: No one can test honesty, so listing it on a job description is kind of funny thing. I found these companies to be less transparent, actually. I guess they need more honest people because they are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot get any information on the company's salary range: if a company does does not ask for your desired/minimum salary, they will not pay you well, treat you well, and the company is doing bad. Don't think that you can convince them otherwise at the salary negotiation stage. Ask about it as soon as you are talking to a person. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any kind of lies and inconsistencies: don't think that, oh, "that is just an automated message." If you catch any lie or inconsistency in any description or words, you might end up losing your time, salary, or your health when you work with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salary suddenly drops during a negotiation: it would be more accurate to say that the company lied. For a contract position, $1 hourly wage equates to $1280 monthly salary and $16640 yearly salary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company is hiring very frequently for its size: the turnover rate is high and people are leaving. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are being too nice: if they have time to write a nice personal email to you, they are not getting enough applicants. They are not getting enough applicants for the previous listed reasons. The more specialized / technical the career is, the job market is smarter. It adjusts amazing well to a company, both large and small. So these companies must opt to be nice, because it costs them least, in order to attract candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Company is referred by a recruiter with a cold email: A recruiter does not care about your interests, they are interested in getting a slice out of your employment by offering you jobs that are difficult and has a very high standard. I mean why else would a company turn to a recruiter? This will eventually turn into you wasting your time. If you applied directly to the recrutier after seeing the job description, that is a different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is a yellow flag: asking you to do a screening test even before a phone call: it's a bummer, because this should work beautifully in theory, but from my experience, I found these companies to be snobby and do not value your time. Most likely they are asking you to take these tests even without reading your resume. It is a different story though if they are actually talking to you, meaning there it is no longer an automated emails you are dealing with. I would just do these screen tests for my own enlightenment and so far they were indeed didactic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another note is that, just because the company email includes a personal contact information, that does not mean anything. Some does start revealing this info once they get serious, but some just reveal this straight from the beginning. It might be a way to fool you and get all serious and more committed. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="career"></category></entry><entry><title>Specializing as a software engineer</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/specialization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-10T04:32:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-10T04:32:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-09-10:/specialization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://wesleyvanderpool.com/?portfolio=leatherman-multi-tools"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt Leatherman multi-purpose tools" src="|filename|/images/leatherman.jpg"&gt; "This guy ain't going to the Olympics"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always feel insecure about my skill set, but in a good way. It motivates me to learn. Up until now, I just learned anything that was flashing before my eyes. I think this step was necessary because I would never know what I am good at or like until I try! But I have not really thought about how I want to specialize. So I compiled a list so that I could look out for my career and see whether I am honing the same skill. Because more specialized you are, the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://wesleyvanderpool.com/?portfolio=leatherman-multi-tools"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt Leatherman multi-purpose tools" src="|filename|/images/leatherman.jpg"&gt; "This guy ain't going to the Olympics"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always feel insecure about my skill set, but in a good way. It motivates me to learn. Up until now, I just learned anything that was flashing before my eyes. I think this step was necessary because I would never know what I am good at or like until I try! But I have not really thought about how I want to specialize. So I compiled a list so that I could look out for my career and see whether I am honing the same skill. Because more specialized you are, the more rare human resource you become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Task 1. Choose one skill and choose to be 10x better than anyone in the team. If that skill is an add-on item, choose a second non-add-on item and be fairly good at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Product Manager (all addon items)
gathering user requirements
coming up with creative new ideas 
fostering a great working environment 
talking to the business and understand their needs 
translating business requirements/needs to the dev team
driving a team and/or drive a project
managing a project

UI Desinger
designing a good UI (addon item)

Developer
solving complex problems
diligently solving lots of routine problems
automating complex build systems
writing tests
adding the final polish to a project
debugging
starting to code from a blank page
getting along with more difficult members of the team (addon item)

Data Scientist
doing data modelling
analyzing a large volume of data
designing a good database model
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Product Manager will probably have a difficult time proving themselves without any prior experience, because their work is difficult to quantify. I also put &lt;code&gt;add-on&lt;/code&gt; tag next to skills that are difficult to gain respect and build a good experience history on. You know how Amazon.com sells products that are &lt;code&gt;add-on&lt;/code&gt; items? They must be shipped with out with non-add-on itmes. Well, that is how I see these skills to be. If you could accompany it with other skills, or a good team, or even one good partner (e.g. Steve Wozniak), you will be making a dent on the universe.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="career"></category></entry><entry><title>Don't give up on your anonymity</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/anonymity.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-12T11:53:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-08-12T11:53:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-08-12:/anonymity.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"People behave a lot better when they have their real names down. I think people hide behind anonymity and they feel like they can say whatever they want behind closed doors." - Randi Zuckerberg (Sister of Mark Zuckerberg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with everything she says, but I endorse anonymity in a learning/development/professional environment.  I have a lot of people who holds me accountable for what I do. Good thing is that they do not write down everything I say or do. The Internet can. The internet is a difficult place to please everyone and I think that you can lose …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"People behave a lot better when they have their real names down. I think people hide behind anonymity and they feel like they can say whatever they want behind closed doors." - Randi Zuckerberg (Sister of Mark Zuckerberg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with everything she says, but I endorse anonymity in a learning/development/professional environment.  I have a lot of people who holds me accountable for what I do. Good thing is that they do not write down everything I say or do. The Internet can. The internet is a difficult place to please everyone and I think that you can lose your identity amidst of all the information and opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I want the freedom of going back to my cave whenever I feel like it. When I stop blogging, I do not want people to think I have a personal problem, etc. When I stop contributing, I do not want to feel guilt. It is unnecessary stress that does not help anyone. Also when I try new things, I &lt;em&gt;DO&lt;/em&gt; want people to treat me like a novice, be more gracious with my mistakes, and do tell me the details. I also want others to approach me without prejudice. I make silly mistakes because it just happens, not because I want it to. And I do not want to feel stupid about it or fear that it will bring me down in the future. I can be more honest when I am anonymous and thus be more productive as a developer. I already use a lot of my brain power when I interact on the internet. I do not want the perfectionist side of me to take over by revealing my identity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a database professor who wants to learn about computer graphics and joins stackoverflow. Do you think he feels easy about asking a simple question? Obviously no. And what if he makes a mistakes and someone points that out to him? Haha, I could totally imagine the guy trying to wriggle his way out without admiting his fault. Well I do not have that much accountability on my job title, but who knows what will happen in the future? With anonymity, &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/18733017/is-the-a-name-for-redifining-a-class-in-main-what-is-the-merit-in-such-use#comment27607066_18733017"&gt;I can admit my mistake whenever I want without pressure&lt;/a&gt; and that helps everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you are a type of person who needs the motivation to better behave, but I doubt it. If you are debating between anonymity and your real name. I recommend you to choose the former and you have more options later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Your identity is your most valuable possession. Protect it. And if anything goes wrong, use your powers." - Violet Parr (from the movie called Incredibles)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No you are not a superhero, but you can be darn close to one with your computer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="career"></category></entry><entry><title>Why spending more time than you save is okay, and when it is not.</title><link href="https://www.4thinker.com/automation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-01T06:34:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-05-01T06:34:00-07:00</updated><author><name>forethinker</name></author><id>tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-05-01:/automation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/04/29/how-much-time-should-you-spend.html"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt XKCD Automation ROI chart" src="|filename|/images/automation.jpeg"&gt; "XKCD: How Much Time Should You Spend"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am certainly guilty of trying to automate everything, including keystrokes, but I never calculate the time I invest to get things automated. This is because the benefits I leap is not just the time I save, but the knowledge and expertise I gain in the process. If you want to automate something, you must know how it works, sometimes you also need to know the foundation beneath that makes everything tick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more merits. In this society where sharing is the norm, you may never know who can expand on the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/04/29/how-much-time-should-you-spend.html"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt XKCD Automation ROI chart" src="|filename|/images/automation.jpeg"&gt; "XKCD: How Much Time Should You Spend"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am certainly guilty of trying to automate everything, including keystrokes, but I never calculate the time I invest to get things automated. This is because the benefits I leap is not just the time I save, but the knowledge and expertise I gain in the process. If you want to automate something, you must know how it works, sometimes you also need to know the foundation beneath that makes everything tick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more merits. In this society where sharing is the norm, you may never know who can expand on the knowledge you share. I am certainly glad that there is a makefile for a program compilation. You could actually argue that programming itself is automating. People spent time to convert binary into a assembly, then to a higher language, and so forth - now most consumers' instructions are automated so that it can tell the machines exactly what they want - no flipping wires needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would even argue that teaching someone is automation. Here is a example: helping my parents to fix their computer problems. If I calculated my ROI, I would not have fixed their problems myself and moved on. But I explained things to them along the way. And now, the confidence they gained over the years is priceless. And recently, my mother used iPad to communicate with a real estate agent and my father got everything on PDFs to get things organized and processed. So I think my ROI is positive now, but regardless of all that, I am just so proud them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more to automation than saving time and making profits. And If we calculate ROIs all the time, we will be wrong more often than not and we will fail to be true innovators. Just make sure you are doing your dues to put food on the table and get on rolling with your passion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only caution one needs to take when automating tasks is doing a good research of alternatives. For example, there are add-ons for Firefox that merely implements a feature that can be ran by a few keystrokes. I am sure there are people who appreciate the author's altruistic devotion to develop such add-ons, but in the end, the lack of research (both by the creators and users) create noise in innovation and progress - preventing a better solution to be reached and wasting efforts. There is no hard guideline for this, but if your work is not getting any traction, there is a reason for that and do not let your ego or fear get in the way. Take your project down if it means leading people to something better. Well, it is easy said than done, so I am making a reminder to myself here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="lifehacker"></category><category term="automation"></category></entry></feed>