<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Forethinker - life</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:45:14 -0700</lastBuildDate><item><title>My Choice of Hardware in 2016</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/gadgets-2016.html</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;Phone | Nexus 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still running strong after three years. I am waiting for Nexus 2016 with Android N. My folks are still using Nexus 5 with no problem. They will probably get a refresh once Nexus 2016 price drops in about a year after the release. Nexus 6P dropped about 33% in price after 9 months of release. I can't wait for my phone to replace my credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Camera | Pentax K-50&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weatherproof and best bang for the buck in the entry-level camera. I use 50mm prime with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Laptop | Dell M3800&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best laptop I used and nothing else …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:45:14 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2016-06-06:/gadgets-2016.html</guid></item><item><title>Minimalist Camera Setup</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/dslr-camera-lens.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The argument for 35mm vs 50mm is endless and I finally came to peace with my choice.
I own Pentax K-50, an excellent entry camera for a hobbyist. After playing around with the zoom lens kit (18-55), I bought my first prime lens with 55mm focal length.
I did feel some uneasiness when I tried to take group photo, or any indoor photo that needed a bit more landscape. &lt;a href="http://www.pentaxforums.com/forums/58-troubleshooting-beginner-help/259160-my-first-prime-lens-pentax-da-50mm-f1-8-vs-da-35mm-f2-4-al.html"&gt;From the Pentax Forum, 2/3 of the users recommended 35mm.&lt;/a&gt;. I was a click away from buying 35mm lens, but then after some research. I decided to invest more money …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 17:44:16 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2016-04-07:/dslr-camera-lens.html</guid><category>camera</category><category>dslr</category><category>lens</category></item><item><title>What I want in a phone</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/cellphone.html</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;Wanted Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stock Android: Google's Android features get updated very frequently. A lot has change since I first got Nexus 5 and it is still updating earlier than other brands'. Software is the heart of a machine and I would rather choose stock Android even if I have to sacrifice other features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fast charging: I am waiting for Snapdragon 820 really badly right now. Reportedly, Huawei is making a successor to Nexus 6P in 2016 with snapdragon 820. I think this is going my next phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replaceable battery: with the fast charging and a bigger battery, the need for a …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2016-01-02:/cellphone.html</guid><category>phone</category><category>android</category><category>google</category><category>features</category><category>hardware</category></item><item><title>I am addicted to perrier and I cannot lie</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/perrier.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So carbonated water is much healthier than other types of drink for your bones and teeth according to [BBC] (http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20150911-is-sparkling-water-really-bad-for-you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That weak acid, however, seems to be beneficial to my digestive system, especially when I eat a lot after a workout or something. And also that refreshing feeling from the carbonation makes my brain happy. Perrier's carbonating technique seems to be a lot superior to its competitors. The kick is much stronger and it lasts longer after the bottle has been opened.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-12-17:/perrier.html</guid><category>diet</category><category>perrier</category><category>carbonated</category></item><item><title>Why do you bother charging your wireless devices?</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/charging-devices.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I love technology, but there is one trait of a device that is a turn off for me. And that is charging. Okay, I do make a compromise and I understand that I cannot live with just wired devices. Here are a few indispensable devices that need charging in my inventory: laptop and cellphone. My vacuum cleaner does not make it to this list because it has a dock. My kindle... it lasts a month and it gets charged as I think about which book or documents to transfer my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I skip wireless mouse, headset, selfie-stick, battery pack …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 09:43:50 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-12-16:/charging-devices.html</guid></item><item><title>Construction Communication Tactics in Relationship</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/relationship.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from the book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Our-Sexuality-Robert-L-Crooks/dp/0495811793/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1447982849&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=our+sexuality"&gt;"Our Sexuality" by Robert L. Crooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gottman's Constructive Communication Tactics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leveling: stating our thought and feelings clearly, simply, and honestly: preferably using "I" language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing: avoid saying things that are hurtful and expressing only the information that are relevant to the issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validating: facilitating constructive dialogue by acknowledging the reasonableness of our partner's concern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volatile Dialogue: some degree of conflict is essential to the long-term happiness of a relationship. For a long-term relationship (&amp;gt; 3 years), the couple who argued occasionally reported significantly more relationship satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gottman's Destructive Communication Tactics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Criticism: "you" statements that attack's one's character …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-11-19:/relationship.html</guid></item><item><title>Should I get into photography</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/photography.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been seriously contemplating buying a DSLR, especially a Pentax k50, because it is weatherproof and accordingly snapsort, it is fairs pretty well compared to other brand names like Canon and Nikkon. I was about to buy a bundle from Adorama.com because they were on sale and then I stopped. I had 2 Point-and-Shoot cameras lingering in the closet. I hardly used them. I hardly got into photography when I bought decent PoS years back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reasoned with myself. Will I get into photography if I buy a good camera? There was obviously no, but I still was …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 10:11:16 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-04-27:/photography.html</guid></item><item><title>Operating Systems</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/operating-systems.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 13:28:15 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-03-16:/operating-systems.html</guid></item><item><title>Beats Solo 2.0 vs Other earphones</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/beats-solo-2.0.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am listening to my favorite artist with &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00IYA2YRK/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00IYA2YRK&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=forethinker-20&amp;amp;linkId=RDNR3NB74I6GNALI"&gt;Beats Solo 2.0 Wired On-Ear Headphones&lt;/a&gt; right now. It sounds great. Maybe it is because of the bigger cone, I can tell the dynamic range of the song and the bass is very lively. I have never been a fan of on-ear earphone because of their size. I am a minimalist and I like to keep things simple. Also my ears are sensitive to temperature and on-ear earphone does not help in that regard. The voice-cancelling earphones are good enough for me in most cases, and I tend to opt for …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 14:44:41 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2015-01-07:/beats-solo-2.0.html</guid><category>Earphones</category></item><item><title>Heartache of being a Good Sport</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/heartache.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I go through my own share of heartaches. For me, I see an heartache as feeling the emptiness in my heart. It is like hunger, you've got to stuff your heart with something in order to avoid the pain. Unfortunately, often life is not in your control and things are taken away from you, or the things that you were expecting never comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People try very hard to fill up this space, because if they don't they would get depressed or even suicidal. Some people do it with alcohol, sex, drugs, food, work, fame, TV, and while others do it …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 21:04:33 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-12-18:/heartache.html</guid></item><item><title>lighter fonts on darker screen</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/black-on-white.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been debating whether I should have a black background on white. I used to have a superstition that a dark background is always better than a white background. I was so obsessive with this configuration that I changed everything, including a web browser to have a black background. I achieved this by various methods, but I was crazy enough to define color scheme for every tag combination on Firefox Stylish. When I couldn't use Firefox Stylish, I tired CSS inverse method on Google Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it got annoying, because they just wouldn't work perfectly. For example, The Google …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 15:46:39 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-12-06:/black-on-white.html</guid><category>ux</category></item><item><title>Daily Devotional Every Night</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/daily-devotional.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I try to read &lt;a href="http://www.baptistbiblehour.org/resources/devotionals/"&gt;bbh Daily Devotion&lt;/a&gt; every night &lt;a href="http://www.baptistbiblehour.org/resources/blog/daily-devotion-app-iphone-and-android/"&gt;with this app on my phone&lt;/a&gt;. I used to do Our Daily Bread, but I wanted some more challenging words, so I went to download all devotional apps available on Android and tried them all and picked bbh as the winner. Anyway, doing devotional is a habit I formed in college, because when I spend entire day working with numbers and figures, my mind is still in the state of "momentum". As in, sometimes I would wake up in the middle of the night with an headache because I would be …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 15:33:41 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-11-24:/daily-devotional.html</guid><category>devotional</category><category>christian</category><category>sleep</category><category>habit</category></item><item><title>Food for thought if you are learning a new language</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/learning-a-new-language.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You know, I see all these videos for learning English, breaking down the grammar structure and vocabulary for every sentence. Then I wonder, how would a baby take in those lessons? I mean 1 year old baby is no smarter than most of you out there. Okay, my smarter I mean, his/her knowledge base is much less than most of you. Maybe someone could argue that knowing less is an advantage, but in my opinion, such academic way of learning a new language is horribly inefficient. Even if you cannot afford to live in the native country for a …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 04:46:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-07-16:/learning-a-new-language.html</guid><category>language</category><category>learning</category></item><item><title>What should I strive to do as a young software engineer?</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/young-programmer-career.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In college, I took classes that interested me and I think it was the best choice I made for my education. People do not look at my grades anymore and a lot of knowledge I gained in college turned out to be exercise for my brain. So what I see is that the depth of your knowledge pays, but the breadth of your knowledge pays even more if you know how to knit them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In college, I lived as busy as I could be and I had not much room to juggle around once I set the schedule for …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 21:32:50 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-07-13:/young-programmer-career.html</guid><category>career</category><category>engineer</category></item><item><title>Advices that worked for me in my 20s</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/advices-for-20s.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for a job that offers free (healthy) food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a startup company to get the visibility in the company and feel satisfied with your work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even when the rent price is expensive, pay the price to not own/need a car. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of trying to form good habits, block all distractions first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to your imaginary self from 10 years future - then choose your habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't travel too much. Save that for your retirement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for an advice from everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't be afraid to skip things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your expectations low.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read news headlines everyday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep things simple. This allows …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 09:30:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-07-13:/advices-for-20s.html</guid><category>career</category><category>habits</category></item><item><title>Porn is like cigarettes/cocaine to your psychological health.</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/better-without-porn.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I never did drugs in my life, but I have seen their effects, so I am making the comparison. I am not the expert on the topic, but here is the best video I could find on the web: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wSF82AwSDiU"&gt;The Great Porn Experiment: Gary Wilson at TEDxGlasgow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in my life, I thought I could never get away from it. I mean the pleasure (the release of dopamine) is just feels so irresistible because our brain is wired that way. But just as you are able to form a habit (addiction) to it, the steps also can be reversed. You …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 01:01:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-06-27:/better-without-porn.html</guid><category>security</category><category>psychology</category><category>habit</category></item><item><title>My thoughts and predictions on bitcoin</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/bitcoin-rant.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I never owned any bitcoin. I read about it and understand its technical achievements, but I do not see it replacing our current currency system. For our intend and purposes, lets say bitcoin's market price becomes somewhat stable and it has been all mined up. Even at this point, the government has no way of tracking its transactions and therefore cannot back it up or protect any of its financial transactions. Well, that is the whole point of the cryptocurrrency. It cannot be used to provide FDIC insurance ($250,000 per account per person in case of bank run-ons). So …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 09:45:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-03-30:/bitcoin-rant.html</guid><category>finance</category><category>rant</category></item><item><title>My Simplified Investment Guide for Retirement</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/retirement-investment.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have at least a dozen books on investment and for me, they boil down to the summary below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary Chart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; |                     | Roth 401K | Roth IRA           | HSA           | 401K              |
 | Contributions       | Taxed     | Taxed              | Not Taxed     | Not Taxed         |
 | Lowers AGI          | No        | No                 | Yes           | Yes               |
 | Withdrawals         | Not Taxed | Not Taxed          | Not for med.  | Taxed             |
 | Limit (/&amp;gt;50)        | 17.5/23k  | 5.5/6.5k           | 33/65k        | 52k/57.5k (Taxed) |
 | Income Limits (S/M) | None      | 112-127/178-188k   | None          | None              |
 | Distribution        | 59.5      | 59.5               | 65            | 59.5              |
 | Required Minimum    | 70.5      | None               | None          | 70.5              |
 | Maintained by       | Employer  | Self               | Self/Employer | Employer          |
 | Early Withdrawals   | 10%       | 10 …&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 01:31:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-03-29:/retirement-investment.html</guid><category>investment</category><category>finance</category><category>retirement</category></item><item><title>Having a great conversation is like playing a great tennis game</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/conversation.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A great relationship starts with a great conversation, and frankly I am not a great conversation holder by nature. My brother used to get so mad at me for asking boring, straightforward questions that seem to lead no where. But when I think of a conversation as a tennis game, it makes things a bit easier for me to be more sociable person. At the basic level, a conversation is compromised of questioning and answering. Likewise, a tennis game is compromised of serving and returning.  Here is the set of rules I keep in my head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tennis =&amp;gt; Conversation
Server =&amp;gt; Questioner …&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 09:38:00 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-03-03:/conversation.html</guid><category>relationship</category></item><item><title>My Choice of Hardware</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/gadgets.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My choice of hardware is typically based on the software. But there are other reasons too. I tend to overlook the price tag if possible, because I use my devices often enough that the productivity is actually more bigger factor in my choices, but I actually found that the most productive combination I found tends to be economical as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Phone + Camera | Nexus 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock Android Experience all the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tablet | iPad2 Wifi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the only Apple product I use. Its purpose is to replace paper. All my music sheets and books are stored there. None of the Android …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 01:53:00 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2014-02-13:/gadgets.html</guid><category>best</category></item><item><title>How your perception of negotiation could hurt you</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/negotiation.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Book-taught negotiation skill and in-practice negotiation are different ball-game. The book you buy from Amazon, despite its wisdom and anecdotes, fails to address the context that you are in. Yes, it is good to read one, but knowing the value of what you can offer and your alternatives or calculating the risks on a spot is a skill that is difficult to acquire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So no, I can't teach you to acquire that skill, but just tell you my experience. First time out of college, I called for a 6-figure income. I high balled quite bit and I thought the company …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-12-18:/negotiation.html</guid></item><item><title>What does it mean to "have no life"?</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/have-no-life.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I began to hear this term since college. From my experience, it was used as an excuse for something or just a attempt to gain sympathy from peers (who doesn't want to play victim?). I was reading a post by an investment banker on Quora who confessed to become wealthy at the cost of having no life. He was trying to send a message that money is not everything, but that got me thinking... do I have a life? I do not watch TV or video games, but the only place I go on weekends is church. Otherwise, I just …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 10:38:00 -0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-11-17:/have-no-life.html</guid><category>lifestyle</category></item><item><title>Learning Chinese</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/learning-chinese.html</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;Why learn Mandarin?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ihs.com/info/ecc/a/economic-predictions-2013.aspx"&gt;China's economy is gaining momentum&lt;/a&gt; and there are a lot of people who will use Mandarin.
Frankly, I studied Spanish for four years and I still do not think I do not have positive ROI of my time. I managed to get better services and find my way in Los Angeles downtown with my rusty Spanish, but I never had to speak the language in social settings or at work. When I was in college I met a lot of Chinese people and I felt left out whenever I joined their social group. Because East Asia countries …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 07:24:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-10-30:/learning-chinese.html</guid><category>language</category><category>chinese</category><category>learning</category></item><item><title>Single Monitor rules</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/single-monitor.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No matter how good of a peripheral vision you have, you cannot possibly focus on entire surface of 24" monitor. So why then would you want a big monitor or even multiple monitors? Because you have a less-than-optimal setup where turning your head is faster than switching tasks with your hands. If you want to be an expert, you got to become a shortcut-foo master. Just like an expert pianists do not rely on their eyes but their senses, your computer and you must become one via keyboard. Muscle memory is much more efficient than a computer. I have written …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 01:14:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-10-11:/single-monitor.html</guid><category>productivity</category></item><item><title>Life Hacking for Thinkers</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/lifehack.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="pages/aboutme.html"&gt;aboutme page&lt;/a&gt;, I say I am a lifehacker graduate. There is a profound meaning in those words. Back in 2008, when lifehacker.com was gaining a greater public attraction, I was there. I subscribed to their RSS feed and went through most of the articles for almost three years. I became more knowledgeable and wiser with each article, but it also cost me a great deal of time. Now their articles seem recycled to me and now I see that they are not the most efficient ways to get things done. (&lt;a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/10/todont.html"&gt;Jeff Atwood also complains about their todo …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 11:50:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-09-19:/lifehack.html</guid></item><item><title>Desktop Customization is a waste of time</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/desktop-customization.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are designs that are useful, and there are designs that are unnecessary. When desiging something, let each element have a purpose and serve it well. Making a "in-between" design might make it a good marketing-gimick, but it will end up being a waste of time. Yes there is an exception to this rule, like a big phone, but I think it is very difficult to make the case for desktop customization. I would even argue that desktop customization as a harem of design (notorious MySpace customization back in 2007 fall under this category). It's flashy and desriable, but it …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 11:16:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-09-15:/desktop-customization.html</guid><category>design</category><category>complaints</category></item><item><title>Companies that raised red flags during my interview process</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/companies-red-flag.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hey you should take my experience with a grain of salt, but these are the rules I will bind by in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honesty is one of the requirements in the job description: No one can test honesty, so listing it on a job description is kind of funny thing. I found these companies to be less transparent, actually. I guess they need more honest people because they are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot get any information on the company's salary range: if a company does does not ask for your desired/minimum salary, they will not pay you well, treat you …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 09:03:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-09-11:/companies-red-flag.html</guid><category>career</category></item><item><title>Specializing as a software engineer</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/specialization.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://wesleyvanderpool.com/?portfolio=leatherman-multi-tools"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt Leatherman multi-purpose tools" src="|filename|/images/leatherman.jpg"&gt; "This guy ain't going to the Olympics"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always feel insecure about my skill set, but in a good way. It motivates me to learn. Up until now, I just learned anything that was flashing before my eyes. I think this step was necessary because I would never know what I am good at or like until I try! But I have not really thought about how I want to specialize. So I compiled a list so that I could look out for my career and see whether I am honing the same skill. Because more specialized you are, the …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 04:32:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-09-10:/specialization.html</guid><category>career</category></item><item><title>Don't give up on your anonymity</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/anonymity.html</link><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"People behave a lot better when they have their real names down. I think people hide behind anonymity and they feel like they can say whatever they want behind closed doors." - Randi Zuckerberg (Sister of Mark Zuckerberg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with everything she says, but I endorse anonymity in a learning/development/professional environment.  I have a lot of people who holds me accountable for what I do. Good thing is that they do not write down everything I say or do. The Internet can. The internet is a difficult place to please everyone and I think that you can lose …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 11:53:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-08-12:/anonymity.html</guid><category>career</category></item><item><title>Why spending more time than you save is okay, and when it is not.</title><link>https://www.4thinker.com/automation.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/04/29/how-much-time-should-you-spend.html"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt XKCD Automation ROI chart" src="|filename|/images/automation.jpeg"&gt; "XKCD: How Much Time Should You Spend"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am certainly guilty of trying to automate everything, including keystrokes, but I never calculate the time I invest to get things automated. This is because the benefits I leap is not just the time I save, but the knowledge and expertise I gain in the process. If you want to automate something, you must know how it works, sometimes you also need to know the foundation beneath that makes everything tick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more merits. In this society where sharing is the norm, you may never know who can expand on the …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">forethinker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 06:34:00 -0700</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.4thinker.com,2013-05-01:/automation.html</guid><category>lifehacker</category><category>automation</category></item></channel></rss>